<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miguel Martin</title>
    <link>http://miguelmartin.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Miguel Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://miguelmartin.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</guid>
      <description>I have more than 12 years of research experience in building energy efficiency and urban overheating. To investigate their connections, I have integrated sensing, physics, and artificial intelligence across multiple scales, different climates, and various urban morphologies. The sensing methods are automatic weather stations, meteorological flux towers, and infrared thermal cameras. The data collected via these methods serves to either validate physics-based models or train data-driven models. Using the models, I aim to evaluate various strategies to counteract urban overheating and reduce the carbon footprint in cities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor urban overheating and carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/monitoring/</guid>
      <description>For the past five years, I have studied monitoring approaches to observe factors contributing to and mitigating urban overheating. During my tenure at a collaborative research alliance between the University of California Berkeley (UCB) and the National University of Singapore (NUS), I reviewed approaches relying on infrared thermography1 and established Singapore&amp;rsquo;s first rooftop observatory for neighborhood-scale studies2. The rooftop observatory served as the foundation for a project administered by NUS, in which I participate as a research collaborator (see the link here).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</guid>
      <description>I received my Bachelor and Master degree in Computer Science at the University of Geneve (Switzerland). At the end of my Master, I wrote a thesis about humain-machine interactions using brain waves.&#xA;As a first professional experience in research, I worked at the Energy Center of the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne. I was hired in a project to study energy flows in Switzerland. The project highlighted the significant role of buildings in the country&amp;rsquo;s total energy consumption.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model thermal and carbon interactions</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/modelling/</guid>
      <description>In addition to observing urban carbon sources and sinks, I suggest to develop novel models of carbon exchanges between buildings and their outdoor environments, which will extend my previous work on physics-based thermal interaction modeling conducted at the Masdar Institute of Science and Technology (MIST) and NUS 1 2 3 4. To address the computational cost and parameter complexity of physics-based models 5, I collaborated with CMU on machine learning. While faster and simpler, machine learning requires extensive training data and lack interpretability 6 7.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate decarbonization strategies</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/evaluating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/evaluating/</guid>
      <description>Models of thermal and carbon interactions between buildings and their outdoor environment offer a promising perspective for evaluating strategies that reduce building energy consumption and increase urban carbon sequestration. They can thus form the basis of support tools for scientists, industry leaders, and policymakers to create a comprehensive city decarbonization roadmap aligned with Paris Agreement targets. To develop such tools and become a world leader in climate-neutral and smart cities, I am seeking research collaborations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/awards/</guid>
      <description> Marie-Curie Postdoctoral Global Fellowship, European Commission, 2022 Best paper award, University of Tokyo Komaba Campus, Sustainable Built Environment Conference, Tokyo (Japan), 2019 Best oral presentation, University of Tokyo Komaba Campus, Sustainable Built Environment Conference, Tokyo (Japan), 2019 President’s Graduate Fellowship, National University of Singapore, Singapore, 2019 NUS Research Scholarship, National University of Singapore, Singapore, 2016 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forging cool and carbon-sink cities: a multiscale synergy of sensing, physics, and AI</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2025forging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2025forging/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a full data driven coupled scheme to simulate interactions between buildings and their outdoor conditions at the city-scale</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024towards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024towards/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling between detailed building energy models and a data driven urban canopy model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024coupling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024coupling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for urban building energy modelling and climate risk assessment</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024machine/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of interactions between buildings and their outdoor conditions on the calibration of an urban building energy model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024impact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InfraRed Investigation in Singapore (IRIS) Observatory: Urban heat island contributors and mitigators analysis using neighborhood-scale thermal imaging</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024infrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024infrared/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal thermal imaging for scalable non-residential HVAC and occupant behaviour characterization</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/ramani2023longitudinal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/ramani2023longitudinal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrared thermography in the built environment: A multi-scale review</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2022infrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2022infrared/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A physically-based model of interactions between a building and its outdoor conditions at the urban microscale</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/miguel2021physically/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/miguel2021physically/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An integrated multiscale urban microclimate model for the urban thermal environment</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/wong2021integrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/wong2021integrated/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of retro-reflective glass façades on the surface temperature of street pavements in business areas of Singapore and Tokyo</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2019impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2019impact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison between simplified and detailed EnergyPlus models coupled with an urban canopy model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2017comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2017comparison/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-scale urban system modeling for sustainable planning and design</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/lim2017multi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/lim2017multi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new validation protocol for an urban microclimate model based on temperature measurements in a Central European city</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2016new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2016new/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of urban temperature and humidity using a lumped parameter model coupled with an EnergyPlus model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2015estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2015estimation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</guid>
      <description>I am a postdoctoral researcher sponsored by the Marie-Curie Global fellowship to contribute to the mission Climate Neutral and Smart Cities in collaboration with the Delft University of Technology and Carnegie Mellon University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>My primary goal as an educator is to provide a holistic, inclusive, and student-centered education that fosters critical thinking and empowers students to address complex and real-world challenges. In pursuit of this goal, I leverage my unique background in building physics, urban climatology, and computer science to design curricula that prepare students for the evolving demands of architecture and engineering professions. My commitment to fostering critical thinking and creativity was forged during my first substantial teaching experience at the National University of Singapore (NUS).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/summary_vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/summary_vision/</guid>
      <description>To date, my research has primarily focused on building energy performance and urban overheating, utilizing physics-based models of thermal interactions between buildings and their outdoor environment. In light of findings reported in various studies12, I have come to realize that urban decarbonization must extend beyond building energy performance to tackle climate change. Through my participation in the PLEA 2024 conference and review of recent scientific contributions in urban sustainability 34, I have come to understand that new building materials and urban designs possess the potential to transform cities into carbon sinks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEAM</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/beam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/beam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Baselining, Evaluating, Action, and Monitoring (BEAM) project is part of the CoolNUS initiative by the NUS president, University Campus Infrastructure (UCI), and College of Design and Engineering (CDE) to develop a test bed for urban microclimate sensing and modelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCIENCES</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/sciences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Smart City Innovations and Experiments using New Climate and Energy Simulations (SCIENCES) project is funded by the European commission and managed by the Delft University of Technology in association with Carnegie Mellon University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching experience</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Assistant, Geographical Information Systems (GIS) and Cartography (GEO1002), Faculty of Architecture and the Built Environment, Delft University of Technology, Fall 2025 (Instructor: Giorgio Agugiaro) Teaching Assistant, Modeling wind and dispersion in the urban environments (GEO5051), Faculty of Architecture and the Built Environment, Delft University of Technology, Spring 2025 (Instructor: Clara Garcia-Sanchez) Co-Instructor, Autonomous Sustainable Buildings: From Theory to Practice (12-770), Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Carnegie Mellon University, Spring 2024</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
