<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miguel Martin</title>
    <link>http://miguelmartin.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Miguel Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://miguelmartin.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</guid>
      <description>I have more than 10 years of experience in the field of urban climate and building energy efficiency. I have essentially studied interactions between buildings and their outdoor environment using both experimental and modelling approaches. I have conducted various field experiments in the outdoor built environment using automatic weather stations, meteorological flux towers, and infrared thermal cameras. Data I have collected through fields experiments have been used to either validate physically-based models or train data-driven models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor urban overheating and carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/monitoring/</guid>
      <description>For the past five years, I have studied monitoring approaches to observe factors contributing to and mitigating urban overheating. During my tenure at a collaborative research alliance between the University of California Berkeley (UCB) and the National University of Singapore (NUS), I reviewed approaches relying on infrared thermography1 and established Singapore&amp;rsquo;s first rooftop observatory for neighborhood-scale studies2. The rooftop observatory served as the foundation for a project administered by NUS, in which I participate as a research collaborator (see the link here).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</guid>
      <description>I received my Bachelor and Master degree in Computer Science at the University of Geneve (Switzerland). At the end of my Master, I wrote a thesis about humain-machine interactions using brain waves.&#xA;As a first professional experience in research, I worked at the Energy Center of the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne. I was hired in a project to study energy flows in Switzerland. The project enabled me to realize the importance of buildings in the total consumption of energy within a country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model thermal and carbon interactions</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/modelling/</guid>
      <description>In addition to observing urban carbon sources and sinks, I suggest to develop novel models of carbon exchanges between buildings and their outdoor environments, which will extend my previous work on physics-based thermal interaction modeling conducted at the Masdar Institute of Science and Technology (MIST) and NUS 1 2 3 4. To address the computational cost and parameter complexity of physics-based models 5, I collaborated with CMU on machine learning. While faster and simpler, machine learning requires extensive training data and lack interpretability 6 7.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate decarbonization strategies</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/evaluating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/evaluating/</guid>
      <description>Models of thermal and carbon interactions between buildings and their outdoor environment offer a promising perspective for evaluating strategies that reduce building energy consumption and increase urban carbon sequestration. They can thus form the basis of support tools for scientists, industry leaders, and policymakers to create a comprehensive city decarbonization roadmap aligned with Paris Agreement targets. To develop such tools and become a world leader in climate-neutral and smart cities, I am seeking research collaborations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/awards/</guid>
      <description> Marie-Curie Postdoctoral Global Fellowship, European Commission, 2022 Best paper award, University of Tokyo Komaba Campus, Sustainable Built Environment Conference, Tokyo (Japan), 2019 Best oral presentation, University of Tokyo Komaba Campus, Sustainable Built Environment Conference, Tokyo (Japan), 2019 President’s Graduate Fellowship, National University of Singapore, Singapore, 2019 NUS Research Scholarship, National University of Singapore, Singapore, 2016 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/news/nustudelft2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/news/nustudelft2025/</guid>
      <description>On July 14 2025, I organized a research exchange between NUS and TU Delft members. A discussion forum is available here to ask questions to participants of the event.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/news/icuc2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/news/icuc2025/</guid>
      <description>On July 9 2025, I presented my research on carbon dispersion in the outdoor built environment using urban building energy modelling and computational fluid dynamics. The poster I presented is available here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/news/eacwe2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/news/eacwe2025/</guid>
      <description>On June 18 2025, I presented the MORICHI dataset at the EACWE 2025 in Norway. The dataset is publicly availble here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/news/asim2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/news/asim2024/</guid>
      <description>On December 9 2024, I presented my research on the use of machine learning to simulate interactions between buildings and their outdoor conditions during the GNI Symposium &amp;amp; Expo on Artificial Intelligence for the Built World in Munich. The content of the presentation is available here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/news/smartlivinglab2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/news/smartlivinglab2024/</guid>
      <description>On September 13 2024, I presented my research sponsored by the Marie Curie Postdoctoral fellowship at the Smart Living Lab in Fribourg (Switzerland). The content of the presentation is available here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/news/gni2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/news/gni2024/</guid>
      <description>On September 11 2024, I presented my research on the use of machine learning to simulate interactions between buildings and their outdoor conditions during the GNI Symposium &amp;amp; Expo on Artificial Intelligence for the Built World in Munich. The content of the presentation is available here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/news/plea2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/news/plea2024/</guid>
      <description>During the PLEA 2024 international conference in Wroclaw (Poland), I presented preliminary results obtained from detailed building energy models coupled with a data driven urban canopy model. It includes the validation of the coupled scheme and a baseline-scenarios analysis. My presentation was on June 26 2024 between 12:40pm and 12:50pm CET. The content of the presentation is available here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling between detailed building energy models and a data driven urban canopy model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024coupling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024coupling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/news/ccai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/news/ccai/</guid>
      <description>On June 17 2024 between 10:30am and 12pm EST, I gave a talk on applications of machine learning to urban building energy modelling and climate risk assessment during the Climate Change AI seminar series. This session comprised a 30-minute presentation on my past experience and current research and a 45-minute discussion on the following topics:&#xA;Computer science and physics to study urban sustainability Machine learning to predict outdoor conditions Machine learning to calibrate an urban building energy model Machine learning to assess climate risk The content of the presentation can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of interactions between buildings and their outdoor conditions on the calibration of an urban building energy model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024impact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/news/esim2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/news/esim2024/</guid>
      <description>On June 6 2024, I presented my research on the impact of interactions between buildings and their outdoor conditions on the calibration of an urban building energy model during the eSim 2024 in Edmonton (Canada). Please find the content of my presentation here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InfraRed Investigation in Singapore (IRIS) Observatory: Urban heat island contributors and mitigators analysis using neighborhood-scale thermal imaging</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024infrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2024infrared/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal thermal imaging for scalable non-residential HVAC and occupant behaviour characterization</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/ramani2023longitudinal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/ramani2023longitudinal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrared thermography in the built environment: A multi-scale review</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2022infrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2022infrared/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A physically-based model of interactions between a building and its outdoor conditions at the urban microscale</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/miguel2021physically/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/miguel2021physically/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An integrated multiscale urban microclimate model for the urban thermal environment</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/wong2021integrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/wong2021integrated/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of retro-reflective glass façades on the surface temperature of street pavements in business areas of Singapore and Tokyo</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2019impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2019impact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison between simplified and detailed EnergyPlus models coupled with an urban canopy model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2017comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2017comparison/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-scale urban system modeling for sustainable planning and design</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/lim2017multi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/lim2017multi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new validation protocol for an urban microclimate model based on temperature measurements in a Central European city</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2016new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2016new/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of urban temperature and humidity using a lumped parameter model coupled with an EnergyPlus model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2015estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2015estimation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</guid>
      <description>I am a postdoctoral researcher sponsored by the Marie-Curie Global fellowship to contribute to the mission Climate Neutral and Smart Cities in collaboration with the Delft University of Technology and Carnegie Mellon University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Teaching has always been a rewarding experience, allowing me to share my knowledge with students while also learning from them in return. For this reason, I adhere to the active learning pedagogical approach to ensure that students receive the most effective knowledge transfer from me. My dedication to active learning originates from a reflection on my education and pedagogical training. I primarily followed an academic curriculum in Switzerland and Singapore, where a passive learning pedagogical approach prevailed during my studies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/summary_vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/vision/summary_vision/</guid>
      <description>To date, my research has primarily focused on building energy performance and urban overheating, utilizing physics-based models of thermal interactions between buildings and their outdoor environment. In light of findings reported in various studies12, I have come to realize that urban decarbonization must extend beyond building energy performance to tackle climate change. Through my participation in the PLEA 2024 conference and review of recent scientific contributions in urban sustainability 34, I have come to understand that new building materials and urban designs possess the potential to transform cities into carbon sinks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEAM</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/beam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/beam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Baselining, Evaluating, Action, and Monitoring (BEAM) project is part of the CoolNUS initiative by the NUS president, University Campus Infrastructure (UCI), and College of Design and Engineering (CDE) to develop a test bed for urban microclimate sensing and modelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCIENCES</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/sciences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Smart City Innovations and Experiments using New Climate and Energy Simulations (SCIENCES) project is funded by the European commission and managed by the Delft University of Technology in association with Carnegie Mellon University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching experience</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Assistant, Modeling wind and dispersion in the urban environments (GEO5051), Faculty of Architecture and the Built Environment, Delft University of Technology, Spring 2025 (Instructor: Clara Garcia-Sanchez) Co-Instructor, Autonomous Sustainable Buildings: From Theory to Practice (12-770), Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Carnegie Mellon University, Spring 2024&#xA;(Main instructor: Mario Berges) Lecture 5: Energy Use in Buildings (Slides) Lecture 6: Thermodynamics Part 1 (Slides) Lecture 7: Thermodynamics Part 2 (Slides) Lecture 8: Thermal comfort (Slides) Lecture 9: Building Energy Simulations Part 1 (Slides, ZIP, Videos) Lecture 10: Building Energy Simulations Part 2 (Slides, ZIP, Videos) Teaching assistant, Digital construction (PF1103), Department of Building Science, School of Design and Environment, National University of Singapore, Spring 2019</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
