<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Initio - Free, multipurpose html5 template by GetTemplate</title>
    <link>http://miguelmartin.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Initio - Free, multipurpose html5 template by GetTemplate</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://miguelmartin.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</guid>
      <description>I have more than 10 years of experience in the field of urban climate and building energy efficiency. I have essentially studied interactions between buildings and their outdoor environment using both experimental and modelling approaches. I have conducted various field experiments in the outdoor built environment using automatic weather stations, meteorological flux towers, and infrared thermal cameras. Data I have collected through fields experiments have been used to either validate physically-based models or train data-driven models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</guid>
      <description>I received my Bachelor and Master degree in Computer Science at the University of Geneve (Switzerland). At the end of my Master, I wrote a thesis about humain-machine interactions using brain waves.&#xA;As a first professional experience in research, I worked at the Energy Center of the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne. I was hired in a project to study energy flows in Switzerland. The project enabled me to realize the importance of buildings in the total consumption of energy within a country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/awards/</guid>
      <description> Marie-Curie Postdoctoral Global Fellowship, European Commission, 2022 Best paper award, University of Tokyo Komaba Campus, Sustainable Built Environment Conference, Tokyo (Japan), 2019 Best oral presentation, University of Tokyo Komaba Campus, Sustainable Built Environment Conference, Tokyo (Japan), 2019 President’s Graduate Fellowship, National University of Singapore, Singapore, 2019 NUS Research Scholarship, National University of Singapore, Singapore, 2016 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal thermal imaging for scalable non-residential HVAC and occupant behaviour characterization</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/ramani2023longitudinal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/ramani2023longitudinal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrared thermography in the built environment: A multi-scale review</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2022infrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2022infrared/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A physically-based model of interactions between a building and its outdoor conditions at the urban microscale</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/miguel2021physically/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/miguel2021physically/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An integrated multiscale urban microclimate model for the urban thermal environment</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/wong2021integrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/wong2021integrated/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of retro-reflective glass façades on the surface temperature of street pavements in business areas of Singapore and Tokyo</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2019impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2019impact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison between simplified and detailed EnergyPlus models coupled with an urban canopy model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2017comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2017comparison/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-scale urban system modeling for sustainable planning and design</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/lim2017multi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/lim2017multi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new validation protocol for an urban microclimate model based on temperature measurements in a Central European city</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2016new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2016new/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of urban temperature and humidity using a lumped parameter model coupled with an EnergyPlus model</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2015estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/publications/martin2015estimation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</guid>
      <description>I am a postdoctoral researcher sponsored by the Marie-Curie Global fellowship to contribute to the mission Climate Neutral and Smart Cities in collaboration with the Delft University of Technology and Carnegie Mellon University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Teachning is not only a way for me to tranfer the knowledge I acquired in the fields of computer and building sciences, but also an opprtunity to learn from others. For that reason, I highly encourage students to actively participate in class rather than passively listening to the instructor. Through active learning, I am able to evaluate student&amp;rsquo;s entry level at the early stage of the course, provide adequate feedback and guidance at each important stage of their learning curve, and ensure they will achieve their learning objectives at the end of their curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Sustainable Buildings: From Theory to Practice (12-770)</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/ceecmu12770/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/ceecmu12770/</guid>
      <description>In this course, I teach fundamental notions in Building Physics and their applications using EnergyPlus. I also provide guidance to students in their assignments and final group projects. I contributed to the course material for the following lectures:&#xA;Lecture 5: Energy Use in Buildings (Slides) Lecture 6: Thermodynamics Part 1 (Slides) Lecture 7: Thermodynamics Part 2 (Slides) Lecture 8: Thermal comfort (Slides) Lecture 9: Building Energy Simulations Part 1 (Slides, ZIP, Videos) Lecture 10: Building Energy Simulations Part 2 (Slides, ZIP, Videos) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCIENCES</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/projects/sciences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Smart City Innovations and Experiments using New Climate and Energy Simulations (SCIENCES) project is funded by the European commission and managed by the Delft University of Technology in association with Carnegie Mellon University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching experience</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</guid>
      <description> Teaching assistant, Digital construction (PF1103), Department of Building Science, School of Design and Environment, National University of Singapore, Spring 2019&#xA;(Instructor: Miller Clayton) Teaching assistant, Project in software engineering (CS 13X008), Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Sciences, University of Geneva, Spring 2010&#xA;(Instructor: Marchand-Maillet Stephane) Teaching assistant, Software engineering (CS 13X003), Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Sciences, University of Geneva, Fall 2009 (Instructor: Marchand-Maillet Stephane) </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
