<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Miguel Martin</title>
    <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Miguel Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://miguelmartin.org/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</guid>
      <description>I have more than 12 years of research experience in building energy efficiency and urban overheating. To investigate their connections, I have integrated sensing, physics, and artificial intelligence across multiple scales, different climates, and various urban morphologies. The sensing methods are automatic weather stations, meteorological flux towers, and infrared thermal cameras. The data collected via these methods serves to either validate physics-based models or train data-driven models. Using the models, I aim to evaluate various strategies to counteract urban overheating and reduce the carbon footprint in cities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</guid>
      <description>I received my Bachelor and Master degree in Computer Science at the University of Geneve (Switzerland). At the end of my Master, I wrote a thesis about humain-machine interactions using brain waves.&#xA;As a first professional experience in research, I worked at the Energy Center of the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne. I was hired in a project to study energy flows in Switzerland. The project highlighted the significant role of buildings in the country&amp;rsquo;s total energy consumption.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</guid>
      <description>I am a postdoctoral researcher sponsored by the Marie-Curie Global fellowship to contribute to the mission Climate Neutral and Smart Cities in collaboration with the Delft University of Technology and Carnegie Mellon University.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
