<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Miguel Martin</title>
    <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Miguel Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://miguelmartin.org/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/about/</guid>
      <description>I have more than 10 years of experience in the field of urban climate and building energy efficiency. I have essentially studied interactions between buildings and their outdoor environment using both experimental and modelling approaches. I have conducted various field experiments in the outdoor built environment using automatic weather stations, meteorological flux towers, and infrared thermal cameras. Data I have collected through fields experiments have been used to either validate physically-based models or train data-driven models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/background/</guid>
      <description>I received my Bachelor and Master degree in Computer Science at the University of Geneve (Switzerland). At the end of my Master, I wrote a thesis about humain-machine interactions using brain waves.&#xA;As a first professional experience in research, I worked at the Energy Center of the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne. I was hired in a project to study energy flows in Switzerland. The project enabled me to realize the importance of buildings in the total consumption of energy within a country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/home/subheader/</guid>
      <description>I am a postdoctoral researcher sponsored by the Marie-Curie Global fellowship to contribute to the mission Climate Neutral and Smart Cities in collaboration with the Delft University of Technology and Carnegie Mellon University.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
