<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Miguel Martin</title>
    <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Miguel Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Teaching has always been a rewarding experience, allowing me to share my knowledge with students while also learning from them in return. For this reason, I adhere to the active learning pedagogical approach to ensure that students receive the most effective knowledge transfer from me. My dedication to active learning originates from a reflection on my education and pedagogical training. I primarily followed an academic curriculum in Switzerland and Singapore, where a passive learning pedagogical approach prevailed during my studies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching experience</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Assistant, Modeling wind and dispersion in the urban environments (GEO5051), Faculty of Architecture and the Built Environment, Delft University of Technology, Spring 2025 (Instructor: Clara Garcia-Sanchez) Co-Instructor, Autonomous Sustainable Buildings: From Theory to Practice (12-770), Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Carnegie Mellon University, Spring 2024&#xA;(Main instructor: Mario Berges) Lecture 5: Energy Use in Buildings (Slides) Lecture 6: Thermodynamics Part 1 (Slides) Lecture 7: Thermodynamics Part 2 (Slides) Lecture 8: Thermal comfort (Slides) Lecture 9: Building Energy Simulations Part 1 (Slides, ZIP, Videos) Lecture 10: Building Energy Simulations Part 2 (Slides, ZIP, Videos) Teaching assistant, Digital construction (PF1103), Department of Building Science, School of Design and Environment, National University of Singapore, Spring 2019</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
