<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Miguel Martin</title>
    <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Miguel Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>My primary goal as an educator is to provide a holistic, inclusive, and student-centered education that fosters critical thinking and empowers students to address complex and real-world challenges. In pursuit of this goal, I leverage my unique background in building physics, urban climatology, and computer science to design curricula that prepare students for the evolving demands of architecture and engineering professions. My commitment to fostering critical thinking and creativity was forged during my first substantial teaching experience at the National University of Singapore (NUS).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching experience</title>
      <link>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://miguelmartin.org/teaching/teaching_experience/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Assistant, Geographical Information Systems (GIS) and Cartography (GEO1002), Faculty of Architecture and the Built Environment, Delft University of Technology, Fall 2025 (Instructor: Giorgio Agugiaro) Teaching Assistant, Modeling wind and dispersion in the urban environments (GEO5051), Faculty of Architecture and the Built Environment, Delft University of Technology, Spring 2025 (Instructor: Clara Garcia-Sanchez) Co-Instructor, Autonomous Sustainable Buildings: From Theory to Practice (12-770), Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Carnegie Mellon University, Spring 2024</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
